ahealthiermichigan.org 2010-06-25

# Privacy Policy | A Healthier Michigan: The online community for healthy conversations.

**Notice of Privacy Practices**   
Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan understands the importance of keeping your health information private. We follow strict privacy policies in accordance with state and federal law. For example, we never sell your health information to anyone or release it to any company who may want to sell products to you. If you have questions or would like additional information regarding our privacy practices, please call 313-225-9000. 

  **HIPAA**   
Our HIPAA [Notice of Privacy Practices (56K PDF)](http://bcbsm.com/pdf/npp_nongroup_underwr.pdf) http://bcbsm.com/pdf/npp_nongroup_underwr.pdf details our privacy practices and your rights with respect to the handling of your personal information in accordance with the Health Insurance Portability & Accountability Act (HIPAA).   
To exercise your rights under the HIPAA Privacy rule (for example, to authorize BCBSM or BCN to discuss your private health information with someone else on your behalf, to request confidential communications, to register a privacy complaint, etc.), [visit our Privacy Forms page](http://bcbsm.com/home/privacy_practice/forms.shtml). http://bcbsm.com/home/privacy_practice/forms.shtml 

  **Privacy Practices for Internet-Based Communications**   
When you use the Internet to communicate with us, we make the following pledge:   
* We consider any and all Internet communications as private and confidential unless otherwise clearly stated.   
* We will monitor and audit security controls to ensure that Internet privacy protection is maximized at all times.   
* We will publish our Internet security and privacy practices as new technologies evolve. 

  **Personal Information the Blues Collect, and How It Is Used**   
The Blues collect information from users of our site. We use personal information to customize your Internet transaction. Generally, we do not share with third parties the personal information you supply when conducting transactions on our Web site. And generally, unless you specifically key in personal information on our Web site, you browse our Web site anonymously, which means personal information is not collected. We may collect your personal information, such as name, address, etc. using a secure session when you initially register with us at this Web site or if you engage in a transaction that requires an electronic signature, for example.   
In addition to personal information, we also gather information on the use of our Web site, including domain name, number of hits, pages visited, length of user session, and so forth to evaluate the usefulness of our site. 

  **Protecting Online Interactions**   
When you use our online services, you may be asked to provide personal information that is necessary for us to process your request. To ensure your transaction remains confidential, the information is sent to us using an encrypted form in a "secure session" established with Secure Socket Layer (SSL). We also require the use of authentication, such as user ID and password, which allows us to verify your identity when you access our online services. We also use firewall technology to safeguard your information from outside access. 

  Security Tips:   
* Choose unique passwords. Don't use your Social Security number, birth date, middle name, names of spouse or children, or anything else that someone could easily guess as a password.   
* Do not share your user ID and password with anyone else.   
* After you have submitted information online, we recommend that you close your browser before leaving your computer. This practice ensures you are not leaving personally identifiable information on the computer for those who may use it after you. This is especially important if you are using a computer in a public place.   
* Do not leave your computer unattended during an online session.   
* Contact us immediately at 1-877-258-3932 if you suspect that someone has accessed your information online without your authorization. 

  **E-mail**   
We do not offer encrypted Internet e-mail. As a result, when our Web site users send e-mail inquiries to us, the return e-mail address may be used to respond to the e-mail inquiry. We do not use the return e-mail address for any other purpose, nor will we share it with any third parties.   
For private inquiries including those containing Protected Health Information, [contact Customer Service](http://bcbsm.com/member/contact_us/). http://bcbsm.com/member/contact_us/ 

  **Voluntary Online Customer Surveys**   
We periodically conduct two types of surveys on our corporate Web site. General surveys on our site are randomly generated for all users. Specific surveys are offered to Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan members only within the secure member area.   
We encourage you to participate in these surveys because they provide us with important information to improve the services we offer. Your personal information and responses remain strictly confidential. Participation in our surveys is voluntary.   
All responses to our surveys are aggregated to create summarized results (such as gender, age, or other demographic information). We then use the summarized results to improve the quality of our services to you. 

  **About Cookies**   
What is a cookie?   
A "cookie" is a piece of information that is sent to your browser along with a web page when you sign-on to a website. It is a unique identifier that a web server places on your computer. There are two types of cookies, (1) session cookies and (2) persistent cookies.   
A session cookie is a text string (line of text) that is stored in computer memory temporarily. Session cookies are used to enable a web site to track the pages you visit during a session so that information can be customized for you. Once you exit the website, the session cookie is destroyed.   
Persistent cookies are small files used by a web server to deliver data to a Web client (user); request that the client store the information; and in certain circumstances, return the information to the web site. Web sites can thus "remember" user information, for example their preferences for a particular web site, and allow the use of user passwords. The web site may deliver one or more cookies to the client. The client stores cookie data in one or more files on its local hard drive. In most cases the user can control a client browser to allow the use of cookies or disallow its use. Disallowing cookies may negatively impact intended functionality of web pages on this website. 

  **About Banner Ads**   
Any site banner ads link you to areas of interest only within our Web site. We do not show banner ads for external Web sites. 

  **Links From Our Site**   
We have links from our Web site to a number of different health care-related sites. We provide these links as a courtesy to help you find information. We are not responsible for the performance or content of sites linked from BCBSM.com since they are beyond our control. We recommend you read the privacy statements on the sites you visit to understand their individual privacy practices. 

  **Protecting Children**   
In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we do not knowingly solicit data from children under 18 years of age, and we do not knowingly market to children under 18 years of age.   
We recognize that protecting children's identities and privacy online is important and that the responsibility to do so rests with both the online industry and with parents. 

  **Where to Direct Questions About Our Online Privacy Practices**   
If you have any questions about our online privacy practices, call 313-225-9000. 

  **Revisions to Online Privacy Practices**   
We reserve the right to revise, amend, or modify our online privacy practices at any time and in any manner.
